businessmodelgeneration.com 2019-01-24

# Strategyzer | Privacy Policy

Strategyzer AG provides an individual or collaborative service to create, analyze, share, and discuss strategic business issues such as business models (hereafter called "Content"). Furthermore it enables the adding of meaningful metadata and comments to content created individually or collaboratively. 

Strategyzer AG is committed to protecting the privacy of the users and to comply with all relevant laws. This Privacy Policy describes general rules applied to all of our global users as well as rules specifically applicable to EU users. 

### Information Collection and Use Practices

You can choose to make your content public for anyone to access, restrict access to a limited number of other Strategyzer AG users, or keep the content private so only you can access them. 

_Personal Data_

We collect personally identifiable information ("Personal Data") from you when you voluntarily choose to provide Personal Data. We use the Personal Data that we collect in order to provide and improve our services. Examples of Personal Data we collect include first name, last name, address, email address, telephone number, billing and credit card information, and information regarding your subscription. 

_Use of Personal Data_

Strategyzer AG uses the Personal Data you provide in a manner that is consistent with this Privacy Policy. If you provide Personal Data for a certain reason, we may use the Personal Data only in connection with the reason for which it was provided. When we receive your Personal Data from a Strategyzer AG Client with whom you have registered, we may use that Personal Data in order to contact you on behalf of that Strategyzer AG Client (via email or otherwise). Strategyzer AG and its affiliates also use your Personal Data and other non-personally-identifiable information collected through the Website to help us improve the content and functionality of the Website, to better understand the users of our Website, and to improve our services. 

_Aggregated Personal Data_

In an ongoing effort to better understand our users, we may analyze the Personal Data that is provided to the Website in aggregate form. This aggregate information does not identify you personally. We may share this aggregate data with our affiliates, agents and business partners. We may also disclose aggregated user statistics in order to describe our services to current and prospective business partners, and to other third parties for other lawful purposes. 

_Passively Collected Information_

When you interact with us through the Website, we receive and store certain additional non- personally-identifiable information. For example, we automatically receive and record information on our server logs from your browser including your IP address, browser type and language, referring/exit pages and URLs, other browser history, platform type, number of clicks, landing pages, cookie information, the pages you requested and viewed, the amount of time spent on particular pages, and the date and time. We only use this data in aggregate form, that is, as a statistical measure, and not in a manner that would identify you personally. This type of aggregate data enables us to figure out how often users use parts of the Website or Services so that we can make the Website appealing to as many users as possible, and improve our Services. As part of this use of information, we may provide aggregate information to our partners about how our users, collectively, use the Website. We share this type of statistical data so that our partners also understand how often people use their services and the Website, so that they, too, may provide you with an optimal online experience. 

As an example: we use [Google Analytics](http://google.com/analytics) to collect and review this information and to connect with Google Analytics Advertising Features. This allows us to better inform and target relevant groups. Currently we implemented: 

  * Remarketing with Google Analytics
  * Google Display Network Impression Reporting
  * DoubleClick Platform integrations
  * Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting

Information collected by Google Analytics will only be merged with your personal data only if we get your prior consent to do so. 

Google Analytics offers you to opt out of the data collection [here](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout). It is also possible to stop this data collection and information sending in your browsers settings. 

### We may share your Personal Data with:

_Authorized Service Providers_

Our authorized service providers are companies that perform certain services on our behalf. These services may include fulfilling orders, processing credit card payments, delivering packages, providing customer service and marketing assistance, performing business and sales analyses, supporting the Website functionality, and supporting contests, sweepstakes, surveys or other features we offer. These service providers may have access to your Personal Data to the extent necessary to perform their functions, but we do not allow them to share or use any of your Personal Data for any other purpose. 

_Strategyzer AG Affiliates_

We may share information we collect, including Personal Data, with Strategyzer AG-owned or affiliated businesses. Sharing information with our affiliates enables us to provide you with information about a variety of products and services that might interest you. All Strategyzer AG companies comply with applicable privacy and security laws and, at a minimum, in any commercial email they send to you, will give you the opportunity to choose not to receive such email messages in the future. 

_Protection of Strategyzer AG and Others_

We may release Personal Data when we believe in good faith that release is necessary to enforce or apply our [Terms of Service](https://strategyzer.com/terms-of-service) and other agreements; or protect the rights, property, or safety of our Company, our employees, our users, or others. This includes, without limitation, exchanging information with other companies and organizations for fraud monitoring, detection, and prevention. 

In response to a subpoena or similar investigative demand, a court order, or a request for cooperation from a law enforcement or other government agency; to establish or exercise our legal rights; to defend against legal claims; or as otherwise required by law. In such cases, we may raise or waive any legal objection or right available to us. 

### Information Sharing and Disclosure Practices

You can specify whether or not you want your content to be accessible to the public, to a specific group, to a group of selected individuals of your choosing, or if it shall be accessible only to yourself privately (only you can access them with your Strategyzer AG ID and password). 

### Practices Regarding Your Ability to Update or Delete Information

You can delete individual content that you have on Strategyzer AG by selecting the content that you wish to delete, then clicking the delete button. 

Visit your Strategyzer AG account information area to edit your profile, default privacy settings for content, and more. 

_Communication with You_

Strategyzer AG communication is currently managed from your Strategyzer AG o Marketing Preferences and Subscriptions. Visit your Strategyzer AG account information area to edit your email notification settings. 

### Projects

_Ownership of Content_

The project owner is the owner of all created content therein. As the owner of the content he or she has the right to take any action he deemed appropriate. 

_Collaboration_

All work done by the collaborators are owned by the project owner. The project owner has the right to add and delete members to his project according to his judgement. 

### EU users

On 25 May 2018 a new European privacy law, the [General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)](https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection_en), comes into force. It imposes new rules on companies, government agencies, non-profits, and other organizations which offer goods and services to EU individuals or which collect and analyze their data. The GDPR applies no matter where the data is processed and where the organization processing data is physically located. It is meant to strengthen users rights in light of fast technological developments and increased globalization of business operations involving any form of processing personal data. 

The GDPR regulates the “processing” of personal data for EU individuals, which includes collection, storage, transfer, or use. The term “personal data” is very broad under new regulation and extends to any information relating to an identified or identifiable individual (a “data subject”). 

The GDPR also expands the concept of sensitive data (personal data revealing: racial/ethnic origin, political/religious etc views, trade union membership, health, sex life and sexual orientation, genetic and biometric data).  
Strategyzer AG can assure its users that it does not process any of such sensitive data. 

Strategyzer AG is committed to comply with EU data protection regulation and provides its EU users with a number of important assurances, such as the following: 

  * We will keep Your data within Strategyzer AG and our trusted third parties except where disclosure is required by law, for example to government bodies and law enforcement agencies.
  * Some of our trusted third parties may need to transfer personal data overseas. Being responsible for its users personal data, Strategyzer AG always ensures that Your data remains protected and secure when being transferred.
  * Strategyzer AG will process Your data only in accordance with legitimate purpose, i.e. to provide and improve our services. Strategyzer follows Your instructions regarding storage and processing of Your data. Importantly, the consent given by You to be provided with information about a variety of products and services Strategyzer AG offers can be withdrawn at any time.
  * Strategyzer AG users have the “right to be forgotten”, which means the right to require that Strategyzer AG erases personal data about You in certain conditions, including if the personal data is no longer necessary for the original purpose of the processing or if the data subject withdraws consent for the processing. 
  * You will now also have the right, in certain circumstances, to receive the personal data that You have provided to Strategyzer AG in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format.
  * Strategyzer AG has and will maintain technical and organizational measures to ensure security of Your data.
  * Strategyzer AG will notify You of a security incident without undue delay after becoming aware of the security incident.

### Other

When you use Strategyzer AG Services, you are subject to the Strategyzer AG [Terms of Service](https://strategyzer.com/terms-of-service). Please see [Strategyzer AG Support](https://strategyzer.uservoice.com/) if you have questions about this service. This page describes current Strategyzer AG practices with respect to this particular service. This information may change as Strategyzer AG revises this service by adding or removing features or using different service providers.
